How, then, do we slice the last four characters
of this text? Do you remember what we did in the
indexing topic to get something from the end
of a list? We used a minus sign. Let’s try
that here. I will copy the code from line two
to line four, then make the first part of the
slice a minus four and delete the text after the
colon. This iteration of a slice is saying slice
four characters, starting at the end of the text.
I will rerun the code, and the last result brings
us the four characters at the end of the serial
number. Before we go any further, you may wonder,
why is the number before the colon? Here’s what
I think to remember this, compared to the first
slice. This slice mirrors this slice because
we have a negative number here. Think of it as
starting from the end, the right side, and working
back four characters. The last type of slice,
to slice characters in the middle of a value,
may take a little practice. We want to slice the
characters in the middle, 2222-3333. I will start
another print statement for the serial number on
line 5 and add the square brackets in anticipation
of the slice. What character do you think we need
to start with? Remember, Python is zero-based,
so if we count 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, we need to start
with character 5, the first two. The number after
the colon represents the character number to end
the slice. All you need to figure out is this:
how many characters do we need? We have eight
numbers and a dash, making nine characters.
We need to add nine to the first number, five,
to get 14. I will rerun this code, and the last
result gives us the characters we want. Rather
than try to count what character you need for
the ending point, add the number you need to the
first number in the slice, and you can easily
slice characters out of the middle of a value.